In order to better follow the operation in the tutorial, please reset your user settings or make sure that the mouse preset is the three common mouse presets.
If you do not know how to change the settings, please watch our UI video tutorial first.
Today we will introduce how to make clothes and game costumes efficiently in Marvelous Designer.
When you complete the creation of your costume, and ensure that there will be no additional modifications, you can proceed to the next step.
Save the current project file separately,
and export the current project file.
Save the current costume as a high-model to prepare the details on the low-model.
After selecting all the costumes, export them to the object model and modify the name of the high-model file.
When exporting, please ensure that you select the same UV coordinates.
Because I want to export the model to Maya, we need to set the unit to centimeters.
For this purpose, we need to export the model to a ring.
Before exporting the model, the machine will also select the left command.
Press OK, then mode up.
Since the structure of the clothing panel is more complex, we need to decouple it manually.
When creating the decoupling, I hope that at the edge, such as the sleeve, there is a relatively clean cloth line and circular surface.
In MD, when decoupling, it is important to note that the number of points on the edge of the two related panels must be the same, and that the position can be right.
In this way, it is convenient for us to quickly combine the top points of its edge in Maya.
One of the advantages of decoupling in MD is that every time a panel is decoupled,
if the panel has a sewing relationship, it will automatically be in another panel.
In this way, the corresponding sewing area of the panel is made into a blue decoupling support point.
When the panel is finished, we can use the edit decoupling tool to reset the grid on the panel.
Here I choose the column.
If you choose to replace it, it will decouple.
And replace the original created panel.
After the decoupling panel is completed, we need to edit the UV.
Open the UV editor, we can notice that the UV array is more messy.
In the UV window, click the right button, you can reset the UV to the position of the panel in the 2D window.
This is why it is necessary to arrange the position of the panel in the 2D window in advance.
Please make sure that UV is in the first line.
Since the panels in the 2D window are overlapping, so UV is also overlapping.
You can directly select UV and put them in the first line.
Next, we want to add a done panel.
Here we place a new stand.
This is a mold for theThis is a mold for the
This is a mold for the
Next, we have to put the model.
If you choose to replace it, you can directly select the export model and then export it as an OBJ model after selecting all the TORP versions.
Please refer to the settings in the video for the export options, which are consistent with the settings when exporting high-end models.
Insert the costume and TORP model into Maya.
First of all, the first thing you need to do is to open the space editor.
In the editor, I will delete the main image.
This operation is to ensure that the path of the model is correct.
I am also used to organizing the assets in the scene well in the early stages to avoid later management confusion.
Next, I will provide a new material for the costume.
For this model, I am going to use the BLIN material ball.
And I will rename the material ball's name based on the model name.
In addition, I will also open the modeling panel.
Under the display menu in the grid, I will select the soft edge.
Next, I will delete the history record.
After the previous work is completed, the next point is to merge the costumes.
Currently, each version of the costume is separated.
We need to merge it after selecting the main point.
This time, the mean will be 5 means.
For the main point mushroom, we use the linear thing as the causal structure.
The max value of each point is 74.
And the here value is also the value of this point.
After we click the close that we select the unsımple point.
After merging the vertices, delete the history record.
At this stage, I will export the model to the FBX format.
Then, I will import the model into Substance Painter to create a sticker.
After opening Substance Painter, I will create a new project.
Here I choose PBR Metallic Roughness Alpha Blend Shader.
Select the model we need to import into Substance Painter.
Usually, I like to switch to a 4096 sticker size, but you can switch according to your project needs.
In addition, here I will switch the hair type to OpenGL, then click to confirm the creation project.
Now the costume has been imported into Substance Painter.
In the display settings,
I will switch to a suitable HDRI sticker.
Next, we need to prepare the model.
Prepare the high-model details on the low-model.
Open the sticker panel and click to prepare the model sticker.
In the window, we will set the output size to 4096,
because we can import the high-model or low-model stickers at any time in the later stage.
Next, we need to import the high-model pattern into the costume.
Click on the paper icon on the right of the black box to import the pattern.
Select the high-model pattern and import it.
The rest of the settings remain default, then start to prepare the sticker.
After a while, the sticker will automatically be prepared.
The preparation is to show the high-model details of the costume in the form of a sticker on the low-model.
Click to confirm the completion of the preparation.
Then, we can check if the preparation is appropriate.
Since the low-model does not have a button-locking pattern,
the button-locking part has a preparation error,
but I do not plan to re-prepare here.
If you find that your pattern does not have any preparation error,
then you can draw the sticker.
Now, I have completed the drawing of the sticker.
Next, we can import the sticker.
In the spring, we need to set the sticker export path.
Because we are going to import the engine next,
we use the PPS system.
In the spring, we need to set the PPS system.
So, we use PPR Metallic Roughness.
The export format is
After the PNG configuration is complete, select export.
Next, we will see the process of export.
The PPS system is recorded on the PPS system.
Next, we can turn off Substance Painter and open Unreal Engine to make the material.
After opening the virtual machine, we need to import the clothing film and import the sticker file.
When we import, the FBX Import Option window will appear. We can directly click on Import to import.
When we import the model, we will import the fabric ball at the same time.
Usually, I will move the fabric ball to the Material folder.
At the same time, I will import the sticker to the material ball.
Next, we can place the model in the scene.
But we can notice that the model is now flat, without details, and because it is a single-sided model, we cannot see the back of the hair line.
We need to fix this problem.
Open the Material Editor of the Double-Colored Ball.
At the bottom of the left material ball of the Material Editor, we need to display both sides.
Click on Save Material Ball. You can see that it can be displayed normally in the 3D viewfinder.
We need to delete a node of the current material.
Click on Save Material Ball.
In the Material Editor, we can see that the two surfaces are empty.
I will use Texture Sample here.
After we import the node, we will import the previous sticker.
In the right side of the Material Editor, we can add a sticker in the Texture tab.
In the menu next to it, you can enter the name and find the corresponding sticker.
First, we need to import the color sticker.
After importing the sticker, I need to memorize it as Diffuse.
This will let me know the corresponding stickers for each node.
Connect the RGB of the color sticker to Base Color.
I will use the same method to add other stickers.
In this file, I will use color, hair line, metal and roughness stickers.
I will import them one by one into the project file.
After importing all the nodes and stickers, I will connect them to the corresponding channels.
After connecting all the nodes, we click Save and update the material ball.
We can notice that the current clothing display is a bit strange, too smooth, and the display is not correct.
Therefore, I need to make an actual material to correct the material performance.
We create an actual material ball in the content browser.
After creating an actual material ball,
the clothing will be displayed normally.
This is the basic game clothing production process.